<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title></title>
 <link href="http://www.icj-consortium.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.icj-consortium.org/"/>
 <updated>2015-03-20T17:31:17-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.icj-consortium.org</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Addressing Sexual and Gender-Based Crimes - The State-of-the-Art and Ways Forward</title>
   <link href="http://www.icj-consortium.org/event/2015/03/25/Addressing-SGBC-State-of-the-Art-and-Ways-Forward/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.icj-consortium.org/event/2015/03/25/Addressing-SGBC-State-of-the-Art-and-Ways-Forward</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Hague, The Netherlands, 25 March 2015, 6-7pm – The Hague Institute for Global Justice, as a member of the International Criminal Justice Consortium, together with Sweden and Botswana – the ad country co-focal points for complementarity – will hold a panel discussion on addressing sexual and gender-based crimes (SGBC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will start with welcoming remarks by Dr. Abiodun Williams, President, The Hague Institute for Global Justice, and opening remarks by H.E. Håkan Emsgård, Ambassador, Embassy of Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Themes to be discussed during the public panel include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How the collective efforts of different actors – such as the ICC, implementers, and donors, in collaboration with national judicial systems – can contribute most effectively in the fight against impunity for SGBC&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The gaps and needs with regard to capacity-building in the area of SGBC&lt;/em&gt;; and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to develop and implement SGBC policies on the basis of evidence and lessons learned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;speakers&quot;&gt;Speakers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabricio Guariglia&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Director of the Prosecutions Division of the Office of the Prosecutor, International Criminal Court&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brigid Inder&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Special Gender Advisor to the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court and Executive Director, Women’s Initiatives for Gender Justice&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michelle Jarvis&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Principal Legal Counsel, International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgitta Weibahr&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Senior Policy Expert on Democracy and Human Rights, Swedish International Development Organisation (SIDA)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Jelke Boesten&lt;/strong&gt; (moderator), &lt;em&gt;Senior Lecturer in Emerging Economies and International Development, King’s College London&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;registration-is-required-so-we-kindly-ask-interested-parties-to-register-at-the-following-link---registerhttpwwweventbritecomepublic-panel-sexual-and-gender-based-crimes-sgbc-the-state-of-the-art-and-ways-forward-registration-15925401304&quot;&gt;Registration is required, so we kindly ask interested parties to register at the following link - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eventbrite.com/e/public-panel-sexual-and-gender-based-crimes-sgbc-the-state-of-the-art-and-ways-forward-registration-15925401304&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Register&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second part of an event on “Sexual and Gender-Based Crimes (SGBC): The State-of-the-Art and Ways Forward”. The preceding event is an invitation-only roundtable for experts. More information about this event can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://thehagueinstituteforglobaljustice.org/index.php?page=Events-Events-Upcoming_events-High-Level_Roundtable:_Addressing_Sexual_and_Gender-Based_Crimes&amp;amp;pid=123&amp;amp;id=243&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sponsors&quot;&gt;Sponsors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Embassies of Botswana and Sweden to the Netherlands (the ad country co-focal points for complementarity) and The Hague Institute for Global Justice in conjunction with the International Criminal Justice Consortium. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Promoting Accountability for Human Rights Violations</title>
   <link href="http://www.icj-consortium.org/event/2014/12/10/Promoting-Accountability-for-Human-Rights-Violations/"/>
   <updated>2014-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.icj-consortium.org/event/2014/12/10/Promoting-Accountability-for-Human-Rights-Violations</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On December 10, 2014, the International Criminal Justice Consortium in partnership with the Royal Kingdom of The Netherlands and the City of The Hague co-sponsored an event entitled,  “Promoting Accountability for Human Rights Violations” in observance of International Human Rights Day. This event featured a keynote address by the Honorable Judge Sang-Hyun Song, the President of the International Criminal Court, as well as a panel discussion of experts in international criminal justice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evening event focused on the importance of international criminal justice to the larger human rights movement. Specifically, the event considered the necessity of a swift and effective international justice system to deter future mass human rights abuses. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his keynote address, Mr. Song highlighted the detrimental effect that international atrocity crimes have on society: “[genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes] frequently cause the breakdown of social structures, denying a series of other rights.” Mr. Song noted that the ICC “is not a method for settling old scores. It is an insurance policy for a better future.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aHFC6t9Ccps?rel=0&amp;amp;controls=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distinguished panel members offer perspectives on a variety of facets of international criminal justice, including the process of establishing the Court of Bosnia and Herzegovenia as well as the ability of mobile courts in the Democratic Republic of the Congo to complement the ICC. The entire panel audio is available here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;sponsor&quot;&gt;Sponsor&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Royal Kingdom of the Netherlands, The City of The Hauge, International Criminal Justice Consortium&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;participants&quot;&gt;Participants&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Karel J. G. van Oosterom, Permanent Representative of the Netherlands to the United Nations in New York; Mr. Donald M. Ferencz, Convenor, The Global Institute for the Prevention of Aggression; The Honorable Judge Sang-Hyun Song, President of the International Criminal Court; The Honorable Judge Patricia Whalen, Special advisor to and former international judge of the War Crimes Chamber at the Court of Bosnia and Herzegovina; Ms. Brahmy Poologasingham, Director of Advancement and Counsel, Eastern Congo Initiative; Mr. Matevz Pezdirc, Head, EU Genocide Network Secretariat, Eurojust; Professor Linda Carter, Distinguished Professor of Law at the University of the Pacific McGeorge School of Law and Director of Pacific McGeorge Institute for Legal Infrastructure and International Justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/event-2014-12-10-page-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/event-2014-12-10-page-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
